NIKOLA GRUBOR, MD

Summary:

Medical graduate committed to evidence-based medicine with a passion for medical statistics, Bayesian scientific modeling and pancreatic oncology. Understands the value of good scientific communication, and lack thereof; has been engaged in thoughtful education of the public ever since.

EDUCATION

PhD Student (Medical Statistics and Informatics)

Nov 2022 - Present

Institute for Statistics and Informatics, Medical Faculty, University of Belgrade

Advanced Teaching Skills

Harvard Medical School Postgraduate Medical Education Brigham and Women's Hospital Jun 2023

Doctor of Medicine - MD

Medical Faculty, University of Belgrade Graduate

2015 - 2022

Regenerative Medicine

Mayo Clinic School of Medicine

Jun 2022

Completed the Advanced Regenerative Medicine and Surgery 5210 Course

Regenerative Medicine

Mayo Clinic School of Medicine Completed the Regenerative Medicine 5200 Fundamentals Course Feb 2022

2011 - 2015

IX Grammar School "Mihailo Petrović-Alas"

High school diploma, science-mathematics course

WORK EXPERIENCE

Clinical Research

Nov 2022 – Present

Clinic for Digestive Surgery (First Surgical Clinic), University Clinical Centre of Serbia

Clinical Internship

Sep 2022 – Mar 2023

University Clinical Centre of Serbia

Social media Marketing Intern

Sep 2021 – Oct 2021

DEFINE Digital

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Goethe-Zertifikat B1

August 2013

Goethe-Institut e.V. License 00048-B1J-13-482424

Cambridge ESOL Level 3 Certificate in ESOL International

May 2013

Cambridge English: Advanced (CAE), Grade A

Cambridge English Language Assessment License 0040318554

SKILLS

Microsoft Office Package

R Programming Language

- Tidyverse Workflow, Data Wrangling, Bayesian Scientific Modeling
- *ggplot*, *dplyr*, *modelr*, *brms*, *lme4*

Git Version Control System

Basic Usage for Version Control of Personal Databases

Translation and Text Editing Experience

Six years of experience proofing and editing manuscripts for publication in medical journals. One year of experience editing and proofing a textbook for publication.

DEVELOPMENT COURSES AND CONFERENCES ATTENDED

Attended Radiopedia 2020 virtual radiology conference

Jun 2020

24 hours of online lectures & additional interactive learning

Radiopedia radiology review course

Jun 2020

12 hours of video-on-demand teaching & additional online learning

Completed the Radiopedia musculoskeletal viva practice learning pathway

Aug 2020

Online course (approx. length 5 hours)

How to read a radiology AI paper

Oct 2020

Online course (approx. length 60min)

Completed Pediatric Bone Oncology

Oct 2020

Online course (approx. length 70mins)

Biomedicine Seminar in Petnica Science Centre

2012 - 2013

Upon completion presented work titled: The Olfactory System – a physiological and biochemical review.

Certified in First Aid by Union of Medical Students

2017

Gained theoretical and practical First Aid skills required to perform event supervision.

PERSONAL SKILLS AND LEISURE ACTIVITIES

- Portrait Photography, Blue belt in BJJ, Blue Belt in Judo, Skiing, Cocktail making, DJ-ing, Boardgames, Building Computers, and playing Dungeons and Dragons.
- Built a personal website using Blogdown package for RStudio.
- Contributed to the Zotero public citation library.